BEIJING WU



beijing0128@gmail.com

+1.408.221.2544



Pleasanton, CA 94566



ABOUT

I am an experienced researcher in the biomedical field. My career goal is to maximize the synergy between genomic medicine and biomedical informatics to provide patients with precisely targeted treatment recommendations. I aim to develop tools and quantitative methods needed to discern signals and elucidate patterns in large biological data sets to inform product strategies and guide assay and bioinformatic pipeline development.



EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science
magna cum laude
Pharmacological Chemistry

UC San Diego • La Jolla, CA December 2009 GPA: 3.845



RELEVANT SKILLS



Programming Languages:

C++, Python, R, Bash (Unix Shell)



Data Analyses:

Data Query, Data Cleaning and Preparation, Exploratory Analysis, Statistical Modeling, Machine Learning



Data Visualization:

ggplot2, shiny, matplotlib, PowerBl



Soft Skills:

Problem-Solving, Attention to Detail, Research, Communication (Written, Verbal, and Visual), Convert Data-Based Insights into Decisions, Teamwork



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Principal Scientist

August 2018 - Present

Reagent and Assay Development, Roche Sequencing Solutions, Pleasanton, CA

- Focused on the development of the KAPA Target Enrichment products from business development activities to product launch and post-launch product care.
- Worked closely with software engineers and bioinformatics teams to develop customer-facing data analysis pipeline.

Senior Research Associate

July 2017 - August 2018

Research and Development, GRAIL Inc., Menlo Park, CA

Developed GRAIL's targeted methylation assay to target key informative genomic regions, which allowed targeted methylation analysis of cell-free DNA to detect multiple cancer types, at early stages, at >99% specificity for population screening.

Life Science Research Professional

January 2010 - July 2017

Department of Genetics, Stanford University School of Medicine, Stanford, CA

- Invented Single Cell ATAC-seq (Assay for Transposase Accessible Chromatin) on a programmable microfluidics platform, which analyzes chromatin accessibility at single-cell level, enabling the construction of an epigenomic landscape of human hematopoiesis to characterize differentiation trajectories, and providing insights into gene regulatory mechanisms. This work was featured in *Nature Biotech* and *Genome Biology*.
- Eleven (11) relevant peer-reviewed publications, including second author papers in *Nature* and *Nature Genetics*.

Undergraduate Researcher

January 2009 - December 2009

Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry, UC San Diego, La Jolla, CA

❖ Worked on a biophysical research project on the thermodynamics and kinetics of *E. coli* outer membrane protein folding. Contributed to a publication in *Biophysical Journal*.

RELEVANT COURSES & CERTIFICATION

Linear Algebra for Machine Learning • UCSD Extension

Winter 2019

Data Abstract & Structures • De Anza College

Spring 2020

Decemb

December 2020

Applied Data Science Specialization by IBM • Coursera

Data Visualization Method and Tools • De Anza College

Python for Data Science and Al Data Analysis with Python Data Visualization with Python Applied Data Science Capstone November 2020 Credential ID: WMZV82JT53HZ

Machine Learning by Stanford University • Coursera
Expected Completion February 2021